Guide to the L. Timothy Portwood Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
L. Timothy Portwood papers
1967-2008
SC0966
Portwood, L. Timothy.
6.25 Linear feet
Collection largely consists of his files from classes taken at Flintridge Preparatory School, La Canada, California, 1967-72; as an undergraduate at Stanford University, 1972-76; and at the Duke University School of Law, 1976-79. Files include syllabi, exams, class notes, reading notes, and papers. Collection also includes audiocassette and statement regarding his “Patton” speech given in Meyer Library as a Stanford undergraduate, 1976; his application for the California State Bar exam, 1979; and his retirement speech from Stanford, 2008.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: audiocassette may require reformatting prior to use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
L. Timothy Portwood earned an AB in History at Stanford University in 1976 and his law degree at Duke University. He worked as a lawyer in San Francisco before joining the Development Office at Stanford, where he retired in 2008 as Associate Vice President.
Description of the Collection
Collection largely consists of his files from classes taken at Flintridge Preparatory School, La Canada, California, 1967-72; as an undergraduate at Stanford University, 1972-76; and at the Duke University School of Law, 1976-79. Files include syllabi, exams, class notes, reading notes, and papers. Collection also includes audiocassette and statement regarding his “Patton” speech given in Meyer Library as a Stanford undergraduate, 1976; his application for the California State Bar exam, 1979; and his retirement speech from Stanford, 2008.
Access Terms
Duke University. School of Law --Curricula.; Duke University. School of Law. -- General subdivision--Curricula.;; Flintridge Preparatory School --Curricula.; Flintridge Preparatory School. -- General subdivision--Curricula.;; Portwood, L. Timothy.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Curricula.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2008-361
  - Flintridge Preparatory School, La Canada, CA:
    - 8th grade U. S. history, part 1, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 8th grade U. S. history, part 2, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 8th grade reading (1 of 2), 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 8th grade reading (2 of 2), 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 8th grade Algebra I (1 of 1), 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 8th grade Algebra I (2 of 2), 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 8th grade Latin, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Physical Science (IPS) I and II, 1967-69 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - IPS textbooks (4 v.) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Geometry (selected papers only) 1968-69 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ancient History (1 of 2) 1968-69 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ancient History (2 of 2) 1968-69 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Spanish I, 1968-69 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - English I, 1968-69 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Modern European History, 1969-70 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Spanish II, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - English II, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Algebra II, part 1, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Algebra II, part 2, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Algebra II, part 3, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - U.S. History, summer school 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - History of Political thought, 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - MAS – calculus part 1, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - MAS – calculus part 2, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Spanish III, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Hometown USA: American Regional Literature, Summer 1971 [class cancelled] (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Comparative Governments, comparative economic systems, American Government, 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Physics (1 of 2) 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Physics (2 of 2) 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Spanish IV, 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - English III, 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - English IV, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Term Papers 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Coro Foundation laboratory in Urban Affairs, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Star-News interviews and VP Agnew press conference, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Undergraduate Classes:
    - Communications 1, Mass Communication and Society, Winter 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Communication 140, History of American Journalism, Autumn 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Economics 1, Winter 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Economics 51, Microeconomics, Summer 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - English 87, William Faulkner, Summer 1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - English 173A, Shakespeare, Fall 1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - English 176, Fitzgerald and Hemingway, Winter 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Film, Spring 1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Geology 1, Fall 1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - German 1, Autumn 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - History 5, Western Civilization, Fall 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - History 102, History of Greece, Fall 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - History 128, Central Europe from the French Revolution to the First World War, Winter 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - History 129, 20th Century Germany, Spring 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - History 142, Stuart England, Winter 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - History 151, American revolution, articles of confederation, and constitution, Winter Quarter 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - History 159B, Sectional Conflict in the US, Winter 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - History 165C, the US in the 20th Century, Spring 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - History 192C, Modern China, Spring 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - History 276A, Mexican Revolution, Fall 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - History 299A, Biography and History [dropped at mid-quarter], Spring 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Hist/Poli Sci 135C, How Nations Deal with Each Other, Fall 1973 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Hist/Poli Sci 138A, Arms Control and Disarmament, Winter 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Human Biology 10, Human Sexuality, Spring 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - I.E. 133, Industrial Accounting, Fall 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - I.E. 133, Industrial Accounting, Fall 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - I.E. 133, Industrial Accounting, Fall 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Math 5, Calculus and Probability, Fall 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Music 1, Introduction to Music, Spring 1975 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Philosophy 179, Philosophy of Law, Winter 1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Physical Science 10, Meteorology, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Physics 10, Special Topics in Physics (Development of nuclear physics) spring 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Political Science 10, American Government, Winter Quarter 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Political Science 170, the Supreme Court and the Constitution, Autumn 1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Political Science 172, the Constitution and Economic Justice, Spring 1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Political Science 173, Civil Liberties, Spring 1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Political Science, Criminal law and the criminal system [undated] (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Psychology 1, General psychology, Spring 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Psychology 136, Abnormal Psychology, Summer 1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Spanish 22, Winter 1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Spanish 23, Fall 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - UG Special 102, Risk and Insurance, Winter 1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Analysis of Judicial Decisions [1 of 3] 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Analysis of Judicial Decisions [2 of 3] 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Analysis of Judicial Decisions [3 of 3] 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Stanford Freshman Year (assorted mailings, brochures, etc.) 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Stanford Time Schedules (annotated by Portwood) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Stanford Quad Yearbook, correspondence 1974 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Duke University Law School files:
    - Bulletin, Duke University School of Law, 1976-77 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Criminal Law, Fall 1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Torts, Fall 1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Torts, Fall 1976 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Legal Research and Writing (paper #1) Fall 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Legal Research and Writing (paper #2) Fall 1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Legal Research and Writing, two briefs [ca. Fall 1976] (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Constitutional law 1976-77 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Civil Procedure 1976-77 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Contracts, Winter/Spring 1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Property, Winter/Spring 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Evidence, Fall 1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Business Associations, Fall 1977 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Commercial Law, Fall 1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Personal Income Tax, Fall 1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Regulated Industries, Winter/Spring 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sex Discrimination, Spring 1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Research [appears to be on gay rights issues] (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Research [appears to be on gay rights issues] (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Research [appears to be on gay rights issues] (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Corporate Finance, Winter/Spring 1978 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Jurisprudence, Winter/Spring 1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Corporate Tax, Winter/Spring 1978 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Trial Practice, Fall 1978 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Antitrust, Fall 1978 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Criminal Procedure (paper in lieu of class) Nov. 1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Securities Regulation, Fall 1978 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Labor Law, Fall 1978 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Business Planning, Winter/Spring 1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Legal Profession Spring 1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Trusts and Wills, Spring 1979 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Legal Accounting, Spring 1979 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Remedies, Spring 1979 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - General Info – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Criminal Procedure – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Constitutional Law – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Criminal Law – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Torts – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Trusts – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Civil Procedure – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Community Property – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Wills – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Remedies – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Corporations – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Real Property – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Contracts – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Evidence – Bar Review Summer 1979 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Evidence Rules [undated] (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Motions, Verdict forms, pleadings, etc. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Voir Dire (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Opening Statement (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Michael Lubell (direct examination of) (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Young (cross examination of) (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Legal Research (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Other papers:
    - Meyer Library “Patton” speech: statement and photos 1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - “Patton” speech audiocassette (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - California State Bar application 1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Stanford Retirement speech 2008 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - “Five Days in New York City and Two Days Crossing America,” account returning from New York after 9/11 attacks, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 5)